so Hello guys Welcome to my channel and
I'm R Patrick arbas and I'm a financial
coach in man Philippines So today
we will review this manual future bu
retirement that is our company's new plan
So let's study what are the
benefits What are the benefits that
clients can benefit from
if they take this plan So
Okay Let's start by knowing
what are the benefits that we can
get from
this plan so these are the benefits that we will see
in future boost retirement so first
there is life insurance Of course this is because it is
also an insurance product so a minimum
of 1.8 million The coverage of life
insurance of this plan or whatever age
that falls into
our bracket there is a minimum of 1.8
million life insurance and then Of course it will be
bigger if the plan that
the client takes is bigger so the good thing here is
because there is life insurance ah
you already have protection whatever happens you
know your dependents or
beneficiaries they will receive
that much life insurance immediately with
just ah small monthly premium or monthly
payment later you will know if
How much is it? Next, other additional
benefits? We can add
add-ons like enhance critical
illness benefit, accidental insurance,
hospitalization allowance. But in
my sample, this is just a base plan, so
there is also a premium waiver, which is supposed to be
10 minimum years to pay or pay until
age 60 or until retirement, which is
your target retirement age, and then it turns out that you have 10
years to pay, but
you are permanently disabled, and the remaining 9
years are manual life, which
you will take care of, so you don't have to
worry about it, and then the plan is just as it is,
all the benefits are still there,
even manual life is the one that pays,
because the client is permanently disabled,
so next, of course, the retirement
funding is the good thing about this plan.
It focuses on retirement, so a big
portion of what the client invests
actually goes to his
savings or investment part, so
we will find out later,
so these are some of the reasons
why you should choose to take out
manual life, future retirement, so first,
it's a customized plan.  because it's a plan that
can help with your retirement
funding or your retirement goals because
like I said earlier, it's not
just about saving or investing,
later you'll find out what
its advantages are and then the good thing
here is that we have expert fund
managers who also have the option to
have automatic fund allocation
or in short, it's like if
you put your plan and
your investment in this fund, it's
there for life, but
only if we submit a
reallocation or switching of funds. But
here in the future boost retirement later
you'll find out what the
good thing is, one of the good features of the
plan is 'and then um boost your
retirement Fund with multiple bonuses
because we have loyalty bonuses,
we have premium bonuses, premium
Extension bonuses on top of the return or
interest of your investment, so later
we'll find out too, and then
of course have peace of mind knowing that
you have life insurance coverage for
your loved ones. Of course you're saving for
retirement because mostly you want to be in
the sandwich generation and be
independent here or upon her
or his.  retirement, right? So the good thing
here is that if the client suddenly passes away,
he knows that he will leave something for his or
her beneficiary or loved ones.
Besides saving for your
retirement, you have a big amount to
leave for
them. So we are now in the
investment part. So you can see that
the client is investing
44,000 per year and then you can see
the basic premium, that
means that is what the client is paying into
his plan and then we have a premium
bonus or this is the 5% in the first from the 4th
year to the 10th year, manual life will give
5% of how much
he is paying. So 5% of 44,000 is Php2,500, so that is what
we call the premium bonus that will
be added to the client's investment
and then from the 11th Year to the 20th year,
there will be an additional 2%, so 2% of
44,000 will also be added to the
client's money invested daily. So if it is a
daily investment, but the premium
bonus is  It is only given once every
year and then living benefit as
we can see for example um after 10
years possible because that is just a projection
living benefit or that is
our investment as of that year let's say at age 40
years old the client is 50 so after
10 years of What to invest there is already a
possibility if our um return
averaged 4% there is 360k if it
averaged 88% there is 43,000 if it
averaged 10%
the client has 489 but of course um this is because it is
just our projection it can
go down or it can go up like
our other funds per anum
we have breakfast if
for example the client has paid for 10 years
But this is what I did in my sample
is pay until age or 60 or pay
until retirement age because
we have a declaration for example
our client wants to retire at 55 because
he is still very young So we can
declare there retirement age 55 in
this sample my client is 40 years old
he retires at age
60 So we have an option as to how
long he will invest or will he
drop it for 5 years, 10 years or pay
until retirement Of course it is better
if you have invested and
dropped more So if we see from 40 or
41 until age 60 so a total of 20 years
will fall here That client but if
we look at 60 years old
he also declared that retirement
age is possible at 4% have 1 million and 88%
have 1.6 million and 10% have 2 million So
what if our investment return is still ex
like 15% has 20% so ' but
like I said it is not guaranteed and
just projected because everything Toto
depends on the performance of the
companies we feed like
our peso Global market leaders or peso
us growth fund those who
drink oft Amazon so for example
we have peso growth fund installed bee
SM pure gold BPI BDO so blue Chips
companies of the Philippines  So that's the
good thing, Don, because we're not the ones who are
going to invest here manually, buy and
then sell because we have
professional fund managers, so on the
next page, we'll find out
what else we need to
know about manual life future boost
retirement, so for example, what the client wants is,
I want to have a yearly retirement with a payout, so this is from
60 to 69. So that's
10 years, we'll
invest the client for 10 years. So if
we see that there's a full withdrawal, he can
withdraw in full, there's a partial
withdrawal, and then the death benefit.
Of course, it doesn't disappear. We have
4%, 88%, and 10%, but like I said, it's
just a projection. It could
go down or it could be higher than
those projections. But let's just
look at 88% in the middle. So
you'll see that at 60, here we'll
just look at the partial withdrawal because at 60,
61 can be
13,000 and 62 can be 187,000. So
The client's payout is getting bigger and bigger until
his last payout at 693 13,000 Of course the
client can say 160 if
I divide that by 12 How much is it
in 12 months How much is it So
at 300k it's already quite a lot if we divide it
if we want and the
first payout is only 60 is already a lot we just need to do it we just
need
to increase the monthly investment we will make
for this plan for 5 years for
10 years for until the age of your
retirement like 40 his desired
retirement is 60 so it took 20 years to
interrogate
pay until age 60 20 years to pay so at
least he has saved up a
retirement fund that he can use
for his or her retirement so this
option is the option to withdraw
annually from your account value Or from
your investment fund but we also have the
option to take advantage of it if the client is 66 and fails we will
give him
the money So let's see that so
This is the option to withdraw
in lamp sum So it means that
if we declare a failure at retirement
age 60 at 60, if it fails, we will give the savings to SAO
and then you have invested the
money. So this is the good thing about it, it is
just a failure. So it's up to you if
you want to use it for business or
anything, for example, at 4%, 8%, and 10%,
if at 88% the client has 1.6 million, a
failure withdrawal and then
at 10% the client has a withdrawal
of 2 million or we can see that it is
bigger by that time or like I said, okay.
That's how it is stated there, how the funds
will perform is not guaranteed, so the
values ​​are also not guaranteed, because
unless he has an investment, but the
good thing about this plan is that it has
automatic fund management which will
help to reduce the risk of
investing our money. So let's find out
on the next
page. So if you see this,
we have automatic fund selection and
allocation. In the first year, it was
only 0.08 in the cash fund and then
in the  peso secure 7% those two are
low risk but low return
investments really just below
99% safe and then
our fund managers have a position in equity
Ah the chance of the
client's money earning is higher even if it loses it's okay
because if it recovers it will come back again
So the
client's retirement age is still a long way off and then
we will see as he gets older
those in peso global peso
Global market peso us growth fund or those
in our equity or high risk high return
fund are transferred to peso cash fund and
peso Secure fund let's say after 15 years the
client is 55 years old
he will retire in just five years almost 1.76 and
42% almost 43% of the client's investment
is already in safe fund so to avoid the
sudden fall of equities or high
risk high return It's unfortunate for the client
when he gets close to retiring it will still fall
So will he wait for it So that's why it's
good to transfer to Secure fund So
if we see at age 59 7.98 plus  59
So almost 68 or
69% of your investment is already in a safe
investment or safe fund. So those
in peso global health Global market
and US growth funds or our high risk
high return or equities funds are
only 26% 27% in total. So that's the
good thing here because
we can do it manually, so to speak. This
year you're all in high risk high return,
next year you'll transfer it. So sometimes,
others forget or
they forget to request it from their advisor if
they don't have an advisor, they forget
to request an email because there are
still forms that need to be done for
fund switching and allocation. But this is
automatic. That's the good thing here
because you know that the fund that
your money is invested in is
controlled. Okay, in my Early Years,
that's where the high risk high return is
because I haven't used it yet. And
then as time goes on, it's being transferred down
to a safe investment
just to make sure that
your retirement fund will be safe. And then
there will only be low risk when it
gets closer.  Your retirement, you know,
maybe there will be a retirement.
My money is already at a loss so the good thing here is that it has been
switched into a safe fund
or safe investment. Your money as
your retirement age approaches, which has been
declared, because guys, this is
our retirement age. You are the one who
will decide. You are only 25. You want to
retire at 50. 55. 60. 65. 70. So it depends on you.
You are the one who will decide.
10 years and then pay until
retirement age. So if you are 30 years old,
your retirement is 55. So
you will invest for 25 years. So that is your only option.
So you are the one who will choose. That is the good thing
here. So if you have any questions about Manal
life future B retirement, you can
message me on my Facebook or
email me
or contact me at my phone number that
is in the video. And then at the
same time,
my messenger or Facebook link is in the
description box. It is also in the description box so it is easiest
to access or easiest to message
me on messenger or Facebook.
So I will just put it again.  The
Facebook link is in the description box. So
that's it. Thank you so much for watching.
This is really quick, just a
quick discussion of our future
future boost retirement. So for
example, the withdrawal charges, right?
What about the first 5 years, there is a
withdrawal charge? How much is it? Then, if the
enhanced critical
illness rider who already has top 60
illnesses covered will be added. And then Accidental insurance?
How much will it be when hospitalization is announced?
I'll also include it in my retirement plan.
How much is it? So we'll find out.
You can message me so
you can know more about the complete details.
And then, I'll just insert
this automatic fund allocation.
We also have a manual option. So this is the
only future bus retirement plan
that has automatic fund allocation.
But it can also be manual. It depends on
our client. So, it's good here in
future B retirement, the aut fund
allocation and then at the same time, there is a
loyalty bonus, there is a premium bonus,
premium, Extension bonus, and then there are
choices if the client wants it, like an annual
payout upon retirement or lamsam. So
thank you so much for watching and if there's any
questions?  Don't hesitate to
comment or the easiest way to make sure is
Facebook or my contact number again
thank you for watching and have a
good day